Finding aid to the Helen Gurley Brown papers SSC.MS.00022
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE, 1939; 1950-2001
  - Individuals
    - Cl-Cu: Jill Clayburgh,; Eleanor Clift; Hillary and Bill Clinton; Rosemary Clooney; Glenn Close; Richard Clurman; Alexander and Hilary Cohen; Bea Cohen; Claudia Cohen; Eugene Cohen; Sherry Suib Cohen; Lady Georgina Coleridge; Glenn Collins; Jackie Collins; Judy Collins; Nancy Collins; Pat Collins; Steve Conn; Heather Connolly; Shirley Conran; Barbara Cook; Joan Ganz Cooney; Amy Levin Cooper; Paul Cooper; Bill Cosby; Chris Costello; Jacqui Cotsen; Katie Couric; Warren Cowan; William Craig, III; Liz Crain; Joan Crawford; Walter and Betsy Cronkite; Delores Cunningham; Mary Cunningham; Ruth Curnutt; Charlotte Curtis; Tony Curtis; and Charlie and Christopher Cusack (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Da-Di: Kitty D'Alessio; Maxine Daley; Kay Daly; Vic Damone; Faith Daniels; Mary Ann Danner; Leonard Dare; Saul David; John Davidson; Joanne Davis; Jill Davison; Richard Dawson; Fred De Cordova; Jean Deems; John DeGroot; Oscar de la Renta; Lois Ann Demko; Ronie Dente; Countess Ailene de Romanones; Peter Diamandis; Barbara Lee and Carl Diamonstein-Spielvogel; Joan Didion [Dunne]; Barry Diller; Phyllis Diller; and Edward DiPrete (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Do-Dy: Robert Dolce; Elizabeth Dole; Phil Donahue; Sam Donaldson; Carrie Donovan; Michael Douglas; Maureen Dowd; Edward Reynolds Downe; Hugh Downs; Judi Ellin Drogin; Michael Drury; Peter Duchin; Robin Chandler (Mrs. Angier Biddle) Duke; Georgia Dullea; Faye Dunaway; Dominick Dunne; Clarissa and George Dyer; and Oscar Dystel (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - E: John Eastman; Merry Echo; Owen Edwards; Athenal Ehlert; Lawrence Eisenberg; Lee Eisenberg; Dwight Eisenhower; Julie Eisenhower; Susan Eisenhower; Linda Ellerbee [?]; Dick Ellescas; Inga Elliot; Linda Louise Berlin Emmet; Arthur Emil; Sandra Forsyth Enos; Nora Ephron; Ahmet Ertegun; Charles Evans; Joni Evans [see also SERIES IV. WRITINGS-Books-Having It All and The Late Show]; Peter Evans; Robert Evans; and Judith Exner (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - F: Ted Factor; Lady Mary Fairfax; Lisa Fallon; Musi Farner; Mia Farrow; Judy Feiffer; Michael Feinstein; Fred Feldmesser; Clay Felker; Lessie Ferguson; Sarah Ferguson; Temple Fielding; Freddie Fields; Naomi Findlay; William Fine; Pamela Fiori; Karen Fisher; Ron Fletcher; John Florida; Jane Fonda; Christopher (Kip) Forbes; Malcolm Forbes, Sr.; Malcolm (Steve) Forbes, Jr.; Robert Forbes; Timothy Forbes; Betty and Gerald Ford; Charlotte Ford; Gerry Ford; Reed Foster; Dale Miller Frehse; Betty Friedan; Steve Friedman; Thomas Friedman; Edna Leah Frosch; David and Carina Frost; Lewis Burke Frumkes; Bonnie Hurowitz Fuller; Allen Funt; and Betty Furness (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Ga-Go: Marilyn Galanoy; Ernest Gann; Nancy Tuck Gardiner; William Donald Garson; Bruce Gelb; Phyllis George; Richard Gere; Freddie Gershon; J. Paul Getty; Charles Gibson; Kathie Lee Gifford; Genevieve Gilles; Marcia Ann Gillespie; Elga Gimbel; Rudolph Giuliani; Leslie Glass; Selma Goksel; Harry Golden; Ralph Golco; Leonard Goldenson; Barbara Goldsmith; Mark Goodson; Milton and Maura Gordon; Stephen Gordon; and Robert Gould (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Gr-Gu: Katharine Graham; Cary Grant; Ernestine Gravely; Barry Gray; Adolph and Phyllis Green; George Green; Judy Green; Leslie Greenberg; Gael Greene; Vartan Gregorian; Richard Grenier; Joel and Jo Wilder Grey; Merv Griffin; Helen, Ann, and Steno Grimes; Henry Anatole and Louise Grunwald; Audrey Gruss; Lois and Lee Guber; Jacqueline Guber; Bob Guccione, Jr.; Kathy Keeton Guccione; Maria Guesk; C.Z. Guest; Bobby Guillory [?]; Bryant Gumbel; and Lynn Guzey (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Ha-Hef: Adrienne Hall; Halston; Marvin Hamlisch; Armand Hammer; Alvin Hampel; Jane Hanson; William Harbach; Jean Harris; Barbara [Grizzuti] Harrison; Kitty Carlisle Hart; Jan Hartley; David Hartman; David Hasselhoff; Goldie Hawn; Naura Hayden; Evangeline Hayes; Fred Hayman; Patty Hearst; Randolph, Catherine, and Veronique Hearst; Austine and William R. Hearst, Jr.; Pamela Hedley; Elaine Heffner; Richard Heffner; Christie Hefner; and Hugh Hefner (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Hep-Hu: Katharine Hepburn; Lenore Hershey; Annemarie Herzog; Donald and Marilyn Hewitt; George Roy Hill; Sandy Hill; Gail and John Hilson; Mildred Hilson; Arthur Hirsch; Shere Hite; Bunny Hoest; James Hoge; Lou Honderich; Benjamin Hooks; Bunny (Mrs. Mickey) Hooten; Bob Hope; David Horner; Barbara Howar; Ron Howard; David and Helga Howie; Arianna Huffington; Robert Humphreys; Lawrence Hughes; and William Hunt (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - I-J: Lee Iacocca; Amy Irving; Molly Ivins; Jody Jacobs; Rona Jaffe; Morton and Linda Janklow; Jacob Javits; Peter Jennings; Ward and Julie Jenssen; Aleta Jessup; Ruth (Gerry) Jones; Erica Jong; Vernon Jordan; Irene Josephy; Raul Julia; and Ann and Arnold Jurdem (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Ka-Kn: Helene Kalmanson; Norma Kamali; Harold Kaminsky; Beverly Kanes [?]; Bernice Kanner; Joanne Kaplan; Donna Karan; David Karp; Phyllis Kasha; Masako Katahira; Jeffrey Katzenberg; Elaine Kaufman; Julie Kaufman; Danny Kaye; Dena Kaye; Karen Kayser; Mimi Kazon; Diane Keaton; Bill Keavy; Sally Kellerman; Kitty Kelley; Leo Kelmenson; Edward Kennedy; Jeanne Kennedy; John Kennedy, Jr.; Walter and Jean Kerr; William Kerr; Herb Kerry; Alan King; Larry King; Philip and Jean Kingsley; Henry and Nancy Kissinger; Vera Klawitter; Calvin Klein; Ed Klein; Virginia Kleinrock; Georgette Klinger; Kathryn Klinger; John and Patricia Kluge; and John Knowles (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Koch, Edward
      - General (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Chinese statue correspondence (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Koo-Ku: C. Everett Koop; Ted Koppel; Michael Korda [see also SERIES IV. WRITINGS-Books-Having It All]; Lester Korn; Lynne Kortenhaus; Jerzy Kosinski; Edward Kosner; Elizabeth Kramer; Judith and Steve Krantz; Henry and Carolyne Kravis; Robert Kreis; Florence Kriendler; Peter Kriendler; Joan Kron; Charla Krupp; and Helen Kushnick (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - La: Harriet La Barre; Alan Ladd, Jr.; Joey Lagani; Alan Lakein; Jack LaLanne; Louise Lammlen; Ann Landers; George Lang; Polly Langbort; Kelly Lange; Angela Lansbury; Sherry Lansing; Mary Louise Lau; Estee Lauder; Evelyn and Leonard Lauder; Ralph Lauren; Arthur Laurents; Jerome Lawrence; Mary Wells Lawrence; and Irving Lazar (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Le-Li: Frances Lear; Norman Lear; John Ledes; Ernest and Jackie Lehman; Joe Lebworth; Warner Leroy; Bernard Leser; Jerry Levin [?]; Ray Levin; Ellen Levine; Ruth Levine; Suzanne Levine; Simone and William Levitt; Caroline and Alain Levy; Ed Lewis; Berna Linden; Carol Lindley; John Lindsay; and Brian Linehan (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Lo-Ly: includes Kai-Yin Lo; Jo Loesser; Anita Loos; Shirley Lord; Mari Loshin; Dorothy Loudon; Iris Love; Clare Booth Luce; Mary Luke; Joan Lunden; Carol Lynley and Paul Pourchot; and William Lyons (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Mac-Man: Blair MacArthur; Jean MacArthur; Austin Mace; Shirley MacLaine; Bill Maher; David and Hillie Mahoney; Norman and Norris Mailer; Lee Majors; Pyrrha Malouf; Louis Malle; Nathan Mandelbaum; and Bill Manville (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Map-Me: Fred and Grace Mapstone; Jamsheed and Arnaz Marker; Judy Markey; James Marlas; Alice Mason; Kenneth Mason; Frank Massi; Robert Massie; Virginia Johnson Masters; Carol Matthews; Christopher Maurer; Herbert and Louise Mayes; Barry McCaffrey; Carole Holmes McCarthy; Ruth McCarthy; Sandra McCracken; Marian McDonald; Mary Byrn McDonnell; Cynthia McFadden; Ali McGraw; Phyllis Jean McGuire; Rod McKuen; Ed McMahon; Margaret Mead; Aileen Mehle; Sue Mengers; Lewis Meyer; and Chris Meyers (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Mi-My: Pat Miller; Yvette Mimieux; Grace Mirabella; Mary Tyler Moore; Jessica Morris; Georgette and Robert Mosbacher; Pat Mosbacher; Daniel Moynihan; Martin Mull; Moira Mumma; Anna and Rupert Murdoch; Betty Tabb Hurst and Joseph Murry; and Bess Myerson (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - N: George Nagamatsu; Madeline Nagel; Theodore Nathan; Donald Newhouse; S.I. Newhouse; Paul Newman; Phyllis Newman; Edward and Judy Ney; Carl Nichols; Mike Nichols; Sharon Nichols; William Niebla; Richard and Pat Nixon; Deborah Norville; and Novella (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - O: Conan O'Brien; Katherine Claire O'Brien; Sandra Day O'Connor; Jacqueline Onassis; Ryan O'Neal; Grace O'Reilly; Norman Orentreich; Dee Osborne; Robert Osterman; John O'Toole; and Deniz and Vedat Oztarhan (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - P: Sarvenaz Pahlavi; Alan Pakula; Alexander Papamarkou; Hurley Papcock; George Pataki; Cynthia Patson; Jane Pauley; Barbara Pearlman; Greg and Veronique Peck; Jack Peninger; Mitzi Perdue; Ronald and Claudia Perelman; Anthony Perkins; H. Ross Perot; Bill Peters; Elizabeth Peters; Ray Petersen; Peter Peterson; Guy and Lucille Peyrelonge; Carol Pfeffer; J.J. Philbin; Regis and Joy Philbin; Ivo Pitanguy; George Plimpton; Letty Cottin Pogrebin [see also SERIES IV. WRITINGS-Books-Publisher and agent, 1960s- Bernard Geis Associates]; Beverly Poitier; Patrizia Pontremoli; Frank Price; Hal Prince; Leonard Probst; Emilio Pucci; St. Clair Pugh; and Mario Puzo (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Ra-Re: Glady Rachmil; Al Rachoi; Lee Radziwill; John Raitt; Heather Randall; Tony Randall; Joe Raposo; Dan Rather; Sylvia Rayner; Nancy and Ronald Reagan; Helen Reddy; Robert Redford; Rob Reiner; Ann Reinking; Janet Reno; James Reston; David Reuben; Charles Revson; Martin, Eleanor, and Eugenia Revson; and John E. Reynolds (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Ri-Roo: Abraham Ribicoff; Yvonne Rich; Dusty Rice; Michael Ritchie; Geraldo Rivera; Joan Rivers [Rosenberg ]; Mrs. Charles Robb; Cokie Roberts; Oral Roberts; Shelley Roberts; Jill Robinson; Blanchette Rockefeller; Nelson Rockefeller; Henry Rogers; Kenny Rogers; Peter Rogers; Willie Mae Rogers; Felix and Elizabeth Rohatyn; Betty Rollin; Jeanette (Thompson) Roman; and Andrew Rooney (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Ros-Ru: Maxine Rose; Isadore Rosenfeld; Paul Rosenfield; Abe Rosenthal; Diana Ross; Eileen Quinn Ross; Herbert Ross; Steven Ross; Harriet Rosso; James Roth, Jr.; Roy Rowan; Teresa Rowton; Steve Rubell; and Ann Rubenstein (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Sa: Catherine Sabino; Mualla Sabit; Morley and Jane Safer; William Safire; Harrison and Charlotte Salisbury; William and Virginia Salomon; Jean Salvadore; Alfreda Sanchez; Cristina Saralegui; Anna and Robert Sarnoff; Jerry Saviola; Diane Sawyer; and Leslie Sawyer (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Sc-Sh: Arnold Scaasi; Francesco Scavullo; William Schallert; Dorothy Schiff; Irwin Schloss; Hilda Schneider; Joan Schnitzer; Ian Schrager; Pat Schroeder; Jonathan Schwartz; Stephen Schwarzman; Dennis Scioli; Joseph Scognamillo; Deb Scott; John Clerc Scott [see Larry Baldwin]; Bob Scribner; William Seawell; George Segal; Peggy Seigel; Katharine Seitz; Irene Mayer Selznick; Andrew Shahinian; Gene Shalit; Robert Shanks; Selma Shapiro; Laura Sharp; Veronica Sheehan; Gail Sheehy; Sidney Sheldon; and Dinah Shore (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Si-Sk: Ann and Herbert Siegel; Stanley Siegel; Jack Siegrist; Pat Signorelli; Isobel Silden; Fred Sill; Beverly Sills [Greenough]; Fred Silverman; Ruth Simmons; Dawn Simon; Neil Simon; Norma Simon; Norton Simon; Frank Sinatra; Nancy Sinatra [Lambert]; and Florence Skelly (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Sl-Smith, L: includes Barbara Jo Slate; Zora Sloan; Diana Smith; and Liz Smith [2 letters restricted until 2026 have been removed] (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Smith, R-Sp: Richard Smith; Tommy Smothers; Richard Snyder; Tom Snyder; Kit Solde [?]; Paul Solomon; Stephen Sondheim; Shawn Southwick-King; A.J. Spectarsky; Halbert Speer; Cindy Spengler; and Steven Spielberg (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - St: Leslie Stahl; Francesca Stanfill; Ray Stark; Danielle Steel; Andrew and Lyn Stein; Jules Stein; Gloria Steinem; Sanford Stele; Virginia Dasso Stephens; Leonard Stern; Gary Stevens; George Stevens, Jr.; Martha Stewart; Faith Stewart-Gordon; Jerry Stiller and Anne Meara; Barbara Stone; Harry Stone; Noreen Stone; Betty Strauss; Helen Strauss; Meryl Streep; Barbra Streisand; David Strousse; Lee Strasberg; Kandy Stroud; Jan Struber; Bobbe Stultz; and Geraldine Stutz (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Su-Sy: Arthur Ochs Sulzberger; David Susskind; H.N. (Swannie) Swanson; and Marilyn Symons (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Ta-Th: Gay and Nan Talese; Linda Talley; Madelon Talley; McDonald Talley; Annette Tapert; Dawn Tarnofsky; Iareas Tavou; Elizabeth Taylor; Margaret Ternes; Patrick Terra; Joe Tex; Margaret Thalken; Theresa Thalken; Margaret Thatcher; Helen Thomas; Marlo Thomas; Edward Thompson; and Strom Thurmond (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Ti-Tu: Grant Tinker; Preston Robert Tisch; Robert Tompkins; Bill Tonelli; Jack Tormey; Lyn Tornabene; Jean-Claude Tramont; Viviana Traverso; Marietta Tree; Dorothy Treloar; George Trescher; Carola Trier; Pauline Trigere; Morita Truman; Donald and Ivana Trump; and Ted Turner (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - U-V: Liv Ullman; John Updike; Dolores Urzo; Jack Valenti; Abby Van Buren; Pamela Van Zandt; Gloria Vanderbilt; Patricia Varga; Van Der Veer Varner; Monique van Vooren; Laurel and Pete Vasso; C. Speed and Charlotte Kelly Thompson Veal; Gretchen Verner; Joe Vetrano; Edward Vetter; Frances Vogler; Paul Volcker; Robert von der Lieth; Diane von Furstenberg; and Kurt Vonnegut, and Jill Krementz (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Wa-We: Clint Wade; Jeanette and Paul Wagner; Phyllis Cerf Wagner; Robert Wagner and Natalie Wood; Herbert Walker; Lou Ann Walker; James Coy Wallace; Mike and Mary Wallace; Lew Wasserman; Wendy Wasserstein; Barbara Walters; Sandy Webster; William Weed; Nancy Weil; L. Arnold Weissberger; John Weitz; Raquel Welch; Kathryn Wellde; Linda Wells; Jessamyn West; and Ruth Westheimer (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Wh-Wy: includes Donald Bruce White; Kate White; Michael White; Ruth Whitney; Elie Wiesel; Angela Wilkins; William Williams; Earl Wilson; Phyllis Starr Wilson; Oprah Winfrey; Charles Winston, Jr.; Alex Witchel; Annette Wolfe; Tom Wolfe; Joanne Woodward; Paul Wooland; and Elizabeth Wurtzel (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Y-Z: includes Hunter Yager; Maury Yeston; Tessie and Tito Yulo; Darryl and Virginia Zanuck; Dean Zanuck; Harrison Zanuck; Richard (Dick), Linda, and Lili Zanuck; Robin Zanuck; Bobby Zarem; Merla Zellerbach; Paul Zifferen; Ezra and Cecile Zilkha; Dan Zucchi [?]; and Mort Zuckerman (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Thank you and congratulatory notes, 1968-2000; undated (Box 11, Folder 1-5)
  - Public response and fan mail
    - 1973-87 (Box 12, Folder 1-9)
    - 1988-2001, undated (Box 13, Folder 1-6)
  - General, 1961-2000; undated (Box 13, Folder 7-9)
  - Subjects
    - Early friends, 1939; 1973; 1981; 1997 (Box 13, Folder 10)
      [See also Individuals-Murray, Betty Tabb and Stephens, Virginia Dasso]
    - Genealogy, 1865; 1929; 1981; 1988-89 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Gifts/editor's perquisites
      - 1975-88 (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - 1989-99 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Libraries and museums
      - Miscellaneous, 1975; 1989-2000 (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - Sophia Smith Collection, 1978-2000 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Love letters and poem, 1950-53 (Box 14, Folder 4)
      [See also ndividuals-Bob Brown and Bill Peters]
    - Magazine critiques, 1971; 1979; 1981; 1987-89 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Philanthropy
      - General, (includes Kate Michelman of NARAL), 1968-2000 (Box 14, Folder 6)
        [see also Individuals-Duke, Robin Chandler]
      - Re: church van for Mary Alford from Hearst Foundation, 1979-80; 1989 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Recommendations, 1972-95 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified, 1966-97; undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
- SERIES III. SPEECHES AND APPEARANCES ‡SERIES III. SPEECHES AND APPEARANCES, (1962-2001)
  Material in this series pertains to Brown's presentations in person, or on television or radio. There are correspondence; speech texts; and notes from her personal appearances, including the text of a debate in which she participated at Oxford University. Her television and radio work generated scripts; schedules; and correspondence, including public response mail from an appearance on the news program Dateline. Pilot shows starring Brown, one in the 1960s called Outrageous Opinions and another in the 1980s called What Should I Do?, generated material as well. Television proposals that never came to fruition are filed in SERIES IV. WRITINGS. In the early 1960s, Brown recorded a radio show that was syndicated in Canada. This series contains the complete scripts of these recordings.
  - Television and speaking contracts, 1963-75 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Speeches and personal appearances
    [see also SERIES IV. WRITINGS-Book Tours and SERIES V. COSMOPOLITAN-Advertising and sales presentations]
    - Correspondence, 1962-2001; undated (Box 15, Folder 2-3)
    - Programs and publicity, 1962; 1979; 1984; 1998 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Texts, circa, 1962-96 (Box 15, Folder 5-8)
    - Oxford debate: text, notes, and flyer, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Television and radio appearances
    [see also SERIES IV. WRITINGS-Television proposals and SERIES V. COSMOPOLITAN-Special features-A View from Cosmo]
    - Correspondence
      - 1963-2001, undated (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
      - Response to Sep 1995 Dateline appearance (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - General: scripts, transcripts, schedules, and notes, circa, 1960s; 1975-78; 1985-88; 1999; undated (Box 16, Folder 4-5)
    - Clippings and advertisements
      - 1977-78, 1982; 1985 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - Re: television show Outrageous Opinions, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - Radio spots (syndicated in Canada): scripts
        - 1963 (Box 16, Folder 8-10)
        - 1963 (Box 17, Folder 1-5)
        - 1964 (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
    - What Should I Do? television pilot: correspondence, scripts, and notes, 1987-88 (Box 18, Folder 3-4)
- SERIES IV. WRITINGS, (1940; 1956-2000)
  Besides editing Cosmopolitan, Helen Gurley Brown occupied herself primarily as a writer. Before she wrote the best-selling Sex and the Single Girl, she wrote ad copy, of which a small amount can be found here, and unpublished vignettes and poems. The emphasis on themes of sexuality and independent womanhood is greater in these early unpublished writings than her later published works.
  Brown's collection boasts impressive documentation of her published writing efforts. It contains drafts; manuscripts; newspaper clippings; and published copies of Sex and the Single Girl, Sex and the Office, Outrageous Opinions, Having It All, The Late Show, and I'm Wild Again. Researchers interested in her first two books should consult correspondence (filed in this series) with her publisher Bernard Geis Associates, which includes letters from Bernard Geis and Letty Cottin Pogrebin, and the Lucy Kroll Agency. This correspondence gives an excellent sense of the circumstances that surrounded Brown's sudden rise to fame and the successful efforts of Helen and David Brown to capitalize upon that fame. The correspondence also elucidates the changing world of the media and publishing in the 1960s as well as relatively new strategies of marketing controversial and sexually explicit material. Clippings record the public response to such efforts.
  There are published and draft versions of Brown's magazine and newspaper articles in this series. Material related to a syndicated advice column for single women that ran between the time Sex and the Single Girl was published and the point at which Brown took over Cosmopolitan is of special interest. The series also contains the scripts and LP albums Brown recorded, one an album of advice, the other a recording of a speech. Short pieces that Brown wrote for other people's books and articles and her declines of such requests are found here.
  The unpublished material reveals the breadth of Brown's ideas. Several proposals for unrealized television programs, plays, and articles concern themes that Brown repeated in her published work, but take a more radical approach to them. Fragments of an incomplete autobiography; an autobiographical theatrical piece, which includes an audio-taped interview; and fictional short stories and poems are included among the unpublished works.
  The series also contains letters to the editor, notes, and some writings by David Brown.
  - Books
    - Publisher and agent, 1960s
      - Lucy Kroll Agency: correspondence, 1962-64; 1993 (Box 19, Folder 1-4)
      - Bernard Geis Associates (includes Helen and David Brown, Bernard Geis, Letty Cottin Pogrebin, and third party correspondence)
        - Correspondence, 1961-68; 1989-90 (Box 19, Folder 5-26)
        - Royalty statements, 1962-65 (Box 20, Folder 1)
        - Book tour itineraries and miscellany, 1962-69 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Sex and the Single Girl (includes film version), 1962
      - Correspondence: general and re: film rights and contract, 1962-66 (Box 20, Folder 3-4)
        [See also Bernard Geis Associates and Lucy Kroll Agency]
      - Draft fragment, manuscript, and book (Box 20, Folder 5-9)
      - Condensations and serializations (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Promotion
        - General, 1962-65 (Box 21, Folder 2)
        - U.S. talks, programs, 1962-63 (Box 21, Folder 3)
        - British tour: Telex reports and clippings, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Clippings: general and reviews (Box 21, Folder 5-7)
      - Film: clippings and promotional material, 1963-67 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Sex and the Office, 1964
      - Correspondence (Box 22)
        [See Bernard Geis Associates]
      - Drafts and fragments (Box 22, Folder 2-6)
      - Manuscript (includes original manuscript and rewrites with annotations) (Box 22, Folder 7-9)
      - Manuscript (continued) (Box 23, Folder 1-8)
      - Typesetting copy (Box 24, Folder 1-5)
      - Book (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - Ads and promotion (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - Clippings: general and reviews (Box 24, Folder 8-9)
        [see SERIES VI. OVERSIZE MATERIALS for scrapbook]
    - Outrageous Opinions, 1966
      [See also Newspaper Columns - Woman Alone]
    - Helen Gurley Brown's Single Girl's Cookbook, 1969
      - General: notes, press release, and script (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Manuscript fragment (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Sex and the New Single Girl, 1970
      - Correspondence, 1969-70 (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Manuscript fragment (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - Book (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Excerpts and clippings (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Having It All, 1982
      - Correspondence, 1976-84 (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - Early drafts, 1975; undated (Box 25, Folder 8-9)
      - Early drafts (continued) (Box 26, Folder 1-7)
      - Early drafts, manuscript, and book (Box 27, Folder 1-4)
      - Publicity
        - Tour schedules, 1982-83 (Box 28, Folder 1)
        - Publisher's publicity material and catalogs, 1982-85 (Box 28, Folder 2)
        - Publicity packet, 1983? (Box 28, Folder 3)
        - Best seller lists, 1982-86 (Box 28, Folder 4)
        - Clippings about
          - General (Box 28, Folder 5-6)
          - Reviews (Box 29, Folder 1)
        - Syndication and excerpts (Box 29, Folder 2)
        - Print ads (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - The Late Show, 1993
      - Correspondence, 1986-93 (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - Manuscript
        - Sections not used, miscellaneous draft material, and first draft (Box 29, Folder 5-9)
        - First draft (continued) (Box 30, Folder 1-2)
      - Book (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Clippings (Box 30, Folder 4-8)
      - General: tour schedule and notes, 1993 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Writer's Rules, 1998: clipping and correspondence, 1997-98 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - I'm Wild Again, 2000: correspondence, photo proofs, draft fragment, and manuscript (Box 31, Folder 3-8)
    - General: proposals, correspondence, and promotional material, early, 1960s; 1984-86; 1996; 2000 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper columns
    - Proposals: typescripts, drafts, and notes, early, 1960s (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - "Woman Alone" (syndicated column), 1963-65